Eric Hendrickson

San Diego, CA 92116 · (619) 505-9276 · eric@erichendrickson.tech github.com/hendrickson02 · linkedin.com/in/hendrickson02

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, XML,
 Java, C/C++, Bash scripting, Python, OCaml, Haskell, SPARC
- Testing: JUnit, RSpec, Capybara
- Experienced with Git, Qt Creator, and Android Studio
- Familiar with Windows 10, OS X, and Linux
- Have studied and utilized data structures and algorithms, as well as various design patterns, such as MVC and Prototype Pattern
- Familiar with development practices such as Waterfall, Agile, and Scrum
- Conversant in Mandarin Chinese and Spanish

EXPERIENCE

HidIt — Google Chrome Extension (github.com/hendrickson02/HidIt)

November 2016 - present

- Commissioned and paid for by a college student as a study aid
- Functionality comes from JavaScript and the jQuery DOM
- When a user clicks on a word, it becomes invisible, thus making any web page an interactive "flash card"
- If necessary, the user can also hover the mouse over the word to reveal the word, and upon clicking the word cause it to reappear as it was before it was clicked

Rent-It — *Android App* (github.com/hendricksono2/CSE110W240T10)

January 2016 - March 2016

- App that my team in my Software Engineering course at UCSD created
- Seeks to blend concepts from eBay and Craigslist into a clean, convenient app for the purpose of renting items to others
- Written in Android Studio, used Firebase to manage our database. My role was mostly front end.
- Also utilized various design patterns taught in the course along with Agile and Scrum development practices
- User may create an account and login with username and password
- User may also post and delete listings

WORK EXPERIENCE

Uber and Lyft — Rideshare Driver

April 2016 - present

Works for these rideshare services within San Diego County

Yanbian University of Science and Technology, Yanji, China — *English Conversation Teacher/Team Leader*

August 2011 - July 2013

- Taught English Conversation to Chinese, North Korean, and South Korean students
- Was team leader for my own course, which instructed students with no English language background
- Office responsibility was to manage the computers and software

EDUCATION

LEARN Academy, San Diego — Ruby on Rails Stack Coding Bootcamp

November 2016 - present

Had instruction in the Ruby on Rails and JavaScript development stack and completed various projects using these skills

University of California San Diego, San Diego — Extension Studies/Concurrent Enrollment

January 2014 - March 2016

Completed courses in topics such as Discrete Mathematics, Data Structures, Algorithms, Software Engineering, and others

San Diego Mesa College, San Diego — Computer and Information Sciences

August 2013 - December 2013

Took courses in Java and C/C++

University of California San Diego, San Diego — B.A. in Linguistics and B.A. in Chinese Studies

September 2006 - June 2011

- Double major in Linguistics with an emphasis in Cognition and Language Acquisition and interdisciplinary major of Chinese Studies
- Graduated cum laude with a 3.656 GPA and was awarded a Phi Beta Kappa Scholar.

HOBBIES

- Reading
- Studying history and [human] languages
- Making home brewed mead and beer

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Because I lived in China for two years and even before that studied its language, history, and culture I am someone who can not only see multiple perspectives but can adapt to them and incorporate them into my own life. I believe that this experience will, when married with my programming skills and problem solving abilities, make me a valuable asset to whomever hires me and aid me in the creation of quality software.